本∶噢不,山,维苏威火山就要爆发了!
Ben: Oh no, mount, Vesuviusis erupting!
亲爱的,你抓住孩子们,我要开动战车啦....格鲁格,
Honey you grab the kids, I'll start the chariot and...
格鲁格;格鲁格,太好了,我肯定会得A.
Glug, glug, glug, this is great, I gotta get an A.
开萝尔∶不,你得不到的.
Carol: No you won't.
本∶你在开玩笑吗?我让这些小东西在我一按下按钮的时候就可以动.
Ben: Are you kidding?
然后火山岩就会四处流动.越过罗得斯,
I got this baby rigged to blow at the push of a button.
罗马,
I mean, lava's gonna flow everywhere.
斗牛士,和原始森林.
Over Rhodes, Romans, gladiators, naked virgins.
开萝尔∶但是你仍然得不到A.
Carol: But you won't get an A.
本∶为什么?
Ben: Why?
开萝尔∶因为像你这类人是得不到A的,
Carol: Because people like you don't get A's,
因为他们在学校总是踏步不前,直到他们在社会上找到适合他们的位置,
they just mark their time at school till they can take their rightful
那就是收费员了.
place in society as toll collectors.
本∶把你的脸放在我的火山上再说这些话.
Ben: Put your face over my volcano and say that.
开萝尔∶哈哈哈.
Carol: Ha ha ha.
麦琪∶本,桌子上必须要清理干净,
Maggie: Ben, I need that table cleared off,
我会买很多你爸爸的聚会上要用到的食品回来.
I'm coming back with lots of groceries for your father's party.
本:但是明天我才能考完试.
Ben: But it's not till tomorrow and I haven't even had my first test firing
yet.
麦琪∶马上把你的山从我的厨房拿出去!
Maggie: Get that mountain thingy out of my kitchen, now!
本∶这不是山,是...
Ben: It's not a mountain thingy, it's a...
开萝尔∶你最高只能得C+.
Carol: C plus, tops.
麦琪∶杰森,我们没有收到布兰肯西普的回复!
Maggie: Jason, we never got an RSVP from the Blankenships!
杰森∶我们收到了!理查跟我在办公室说的!
Jason: Yes we did!Rich told me at the office!
麦琪∶你没有告诉过我.
Maggie: Well you didn't tell me.
杰森∶布兰肯西普夫妇明天会来的.
Jason: The Blankenships are coming to the reception tomorrow.
麦琪∶这样的话,就有54个人要来了.
Maggie: OK, then that makes fifty four people.
杰森∶还有约翰生夫妇.
Jason: And the Johnsons, too.
麦琪∶你还有多少人忘记告诉我了?
Maggie: How many others have you forgotten to tell me about?
杰森∶没有了,麦琪!哦,还有施奈德夫妇.
Jason: None, Maggie!Well the Schneiders.
麦琪∶杰森,你说,
Maggie: Look, Jason, how can I plan for this thing if you keep changing
如果要来的人数一直变来变去的话,你要我怎么来做准备呢?
the number of people who are coming?
杰森∶放松宝贝儿,确定有58个人会来,
Jason: Relax honey, that's fifty eight and we ordered food for sixty!
我们已经定了60个人的食物!如果来不及叫备办宴席的人,
Wonder if it's too late to call the caterer and cut back the order.
那我们就少定点好了.只是一个想法.
Just a thought.
麦琪∶杰森,我只是想让每件事情都完美无缺,
Maggie: Jason, I just want everything to be perfect,
我的意思是说,
I mean we don't know these people and I mean, they're important and rich;
我们根本就不认识这些人,他们可是经常要上报纸的重要和富有的人.
they're people you read about in the paper.
杰森∶他们和我们是一样的人.
Jason: And they're no different from we are.
迈克∶哈,当然不同!
Mike: Huh, they sure are!
他们花500美金就为了来我们家留个名.
They wanna blow five hundred Bucks a pop, just to hang out at our place.
杰森∶他们不是花500美金,迈克,他们是在捐赠.
Jason: They're not blowing five hundred Dollars, Mike, they're donating it.
是为了开一个免费的心理健康诊所,这是一件多么有价值的事情,谢谢.
And it's for the free mental health clinic, a very worthy cause, thank you.
迈克∶嘿,如果他们一人肯花500美金的话,
Mike: Hey, if they're dropping five hundred Bucks a head,
那他们应该跳过这次聚会,直接去诊所登记.
they should just skip this party and check into the clinic.
杰森∶让我开门.
Jason: I'll get it.
迈克:妈妈,为什么我们不能早点.
Mike: Hey Mom, how come we never start cleaning a day early for a family party?
麦琪∶因为他们不必喜欢我们,只是我们的亲戚而已.
Maggie: Well, they don't have to like us, they're related to us.
瑙玛∶别挡我的路,重死了.
Norma: Out of my way, it's heavy.
杰森∶对不起,请问你是谁?
Jason: Excuse me, who are you?
瑙玛∶没时间说了,快来不及了.
Norma: No time to talk, I'm running late.
麦琪∶这是我们的备办宴席人,瑙玛.
Maggie: This is our caterer
瑙玛∶很有魅力吧.你想要把这些海鲜拼盘放哪里?
Norma: Charmed, I'm sure.Look, where do you want your sea-food medley?
杰森∶瑙玛,把它放在冰上吧,明天才有聚会呢.
Jason: I want it on ice, Norma, the party's tomorrow.
瑙玛∶不,不是.
Norma: No, it's not.
杰森∶是的,没错.是我的聚会.
Jason: Yes it is.It's my party.
瑙玛∶我的工作定单上写的是今天.
Norma: My work order says today.
杰森∶瑙玛,我只有等到明天才会付报酬.
Jason: Yeah, well my wallet don't start talking till tomorrow, Norma.
瑙玛∶好吧,我让它们腐烂在我的冰箱好了.
Norma: Fine, I'll let it rot in my refrigerator.
杰森∶麦琪,你从哪里请来这个备办宴席人的?
Jason: Maggie, where'd you get this caterer?
麦琪∶杰森,很多人都推荐的.
Maggie: Jason, they came highly recommended.
杰森∶如果他们连日期都记不住的话,
Jason: Yeah, I don't have much confidence in the food,
那对他们的食物就没有多大的信心了.
if they can't even remember the date.
麦琪∶亲爱的,只不过是一个小小的错误,不用想那么多吧.
Maggie: Well, honey, it was a simple mistake, really just relax.
杰森∶不能利用日程表工作的人,
Jason: Yeah, well anybody who can't work with a calendar shouldn't be
也不能做食物方便的工作.
working with toothpicks.
开萝尔∶刚才和我说话的人是唐纳德·特朗普?
Carol: I just talked to Donald Trump?
玛莲∶他是谁?
Mike: Who's he?
开萝尔∶我希望你能在本的旁边建个收费亭.
Carol: I hope you get a toll booth next to Ben.
他在他的直升机上打电话过来,
Well, he called from his helicopter,
说他可能会晚点过来,
he said he was running a little bit late,
但是他说他会在一个小时内到达你的招待会.
but he'd be at your reception within an hour.
杰森∶唐纳德·特朗普!嘿,
Jason: Donald Trump!Hey this isn't gonna be a clinic,
这个可能不仅仅是一个小诊所了,而将会是一个免费的医疗中心.
it's gonna be a free medical centre.
麦琪∶哦,迈克,
Maggie: Oohh!Now Mike,
你看不到我们正在洗垫子,
aren't you glad we're shampooing the rugs and washing the windows and
抹窗户,擦地板吗?
doing the floors?
迈克∶我正在激动呢.那个家伙到底是谁?
Mike: I'm tingling.Well who the heck is this guy?
杰森∶迈克,他是世界上最富有的人之一.
Jason: Oh, come on Mike,
他在曼哈顿拥有一切日本人不会买的东西.他居然在一个小时内就要到我们家了!!
he's one of the richest men in the world for crying out loud.
哇,
He owns everything in Manhattan the Japanese didn't buy.
聚会是明天的呢,开萝尔!
And he's gonna be at our house in one hour!!Wow!The party's tomorrow, Carol!
开萝尔∶哦,但是他说是今天.
Carol: Oh, but Don said it was today.
杰森∶你刚才为什么不纠正他呢?
Jason: Oh, why didn't you just straighten him out?
开萝尔∶因为他说的很自信.
Carol: Well he sounded so confident.
麦琪∶杰森,你百分之百的肯定聚会是明天?
Maggie: Jason, are you absolutely sure this party's tomorrow?
杰森∶麦琪,只是因为富有的,
Jason: Oh, Maggie, you're doubting your husband just because of something
有影响的亿万富翁的几句话,你就开始怀疑你的丈夫了?
some rich powerful multi trillion billionaire said?
麦琪∶这些怎么放呢?是的.
Maggie: How can I put this?Yes.
杰森∶你伤害了我.
Jason: I'm insulted.
迈克∶你会不会搞错时间了呀,爸爸?
Mike: You screwed up big time, huh Dad?
杰森∶不会,我没有搞错,
Jason: No, I didn't screw up, Mike, come on!
迈克,聚会是13号,我们已经念叨了几个星期了.
The party's on the thirteenth, like we've be saying for weeks.
开萝尔∶爸爸,今天是13号!
Carol: Dad, today's the thirteenth!
杰森∶什么?
Jason: What?
麦琪∶是的,杰森.
Maggie: It is, Jason.
杰森∶不是,今天是星期六,明天是星期天,13号.
Jason: It is not.No, today's Saturday, tomorrow's Sunday the thirteenth.
就是13号,哈罗,星期天才是13号.
It's always been on the thirteenth.Hello, Sunday the thirteenth.
麦琪∶杰森,这个日历是 1985年的.
Maggie: Jason, this calendar's from nineteen eighty five.
亲爱的,你不能重新利用这些东西的!
Honey, you can't re-use these things!
杰森∶聚会是今天!
Jason: The party's today!
迈克∶也许这个王牌花花公子可以帮我们抛光地板.
Mike: Maybe this trump dude will help us buff our floors.
杰森∶有58个人马上就要来我们家了,我们只有23分钟的时间来把房子变成一个聚会场所,让我们行动起来,让我们行动起来!!等等!等等!你去哪里?
Jason: We've got fifty eight people on their way over here, we got twenty three minutes to turn this house into a party, let's go, let's go!!Look wait a minute!Wait a minute!Where are you going?
开萝尔∶我想上去为唐纳德·特朗普的到来挑选一件衣服.
Carol: Well, I was gonna go and pick out a dress for Donald Trump.
迈克∶这个家伙穿了衣服的!
Mike: This guy wears dresses!
杰森∶我们能不能不要再想特朗普先生了,还是先想想这里什么事情比较重要!我们只有23分钟,22分钟来准备一个聚会了!
Jason: Can we just please forget about Mr.Trump for a second and think about what's important here!Come on we got twenty three, we got twenty two minutes for a party!
麦琪∶你甚至连歉也不愿意道吗?
Maggie: You aren't even going to apologise, are you?
杰森∶为什么,麦琪?
Jason: For what, Maggie?
麦琪∶你不知道!你真的不知道!
Maggie: You don't know!You really don't know!
杰森:麦琪,二十一分钟后会有五十八个人到!
Jason: Maggie, we got fifty eight people coming here in twenty one minutes!!
麦琪∶他们会发现房子还没准备好,
Maggie: And they'll find a house unprepared for a party,
他们会责备谁呢?是尊敬的,
and who are they gonna blame?
负责的丈夫还是长时间受痛苦的妻子?
The respected, responsible husband or the long suffering wife?
迈克∶会不会责备白痴女儿?
Mike: What about the idiot daughter?
麦琪∶不会,他们只会责备妻子.
Maggie: No, the wife!They always blame the wife.
我认为我的耻辱对你来说什么都不是!
I guess that my humiliation means nothing to you!
杰森∶对我来说很重要的,等聚会完了我们再来讨论这些,好吗?麦琪.
Jason: Oh, it will mean plenty, right after the party, Maggie.
麦琪∶哦,你没谱儿了.
Maggie: Oh, you have no idea.
开萝尔∶我去接,可能又是东尼.
Carol: I'll get it, it might be Donny again.
杰森∶让他在空中多盘旋一会儿.我们还有很多要做,很多!!我将作一张杂务表出来.
Jason: Well tell him to hover.Come on, we got a lot to do here
a lot to do!!I'll make a list of the chores
迈克∶妈妈,别生气了,最少你跟他一起度过了20年美好的时光.
Mike: Well, at least you had twenty good years with the man, Mom.
开萝尔∶不是唐纳德·特朗普,
Carol: It wasn't Donald Trump,
是曼哈顿渣打银行的唯一总裁.
it was only the president of the Chase-Manhattan Bank.
麦琪∶好了,孩子们,我们得使劲干起来.我给备办宴席的人打个电话看看能不能叫她们回来.开萝尔,你负责厨房和浴室的东西的清洁或藏匿,哪种快就用哪种.
Maggie: OK, kids, we got to pitch in here.I'll call the caterers and see if I can get 'em back.Carol, you take the kitchen and the bathrooms and clean things or hide things, whatever's quicker.
迈克∶隐藏会快些.
Mike: Hiding's quicker.
麦琪∶迈克,你把车库中的折叠椅拿出来,
Maggie: Mike, you get the folding chairs out of the garage and get this
然后把这个房间弄整洁.马上,我们开始!
room back together.Now, let's go!!Ha!
杰森∶好了,我已经按字母顺序做好了一份杂务表.
Jason: Alright now, I've made a list of all the chores alphabetically.
如果我们...她留下我一个,带着孩子们走了.
If we all get a...She left me and took the kids.
本∶妈妈,你想看看爆发演习吗?
Ben: So, Mom, you wanna see the practice eruption?
麦琪∶不想.本,我告诉过你把你的山搬到外面去.
Maggie: No.Ben, I told you to take your mountain out of here.
本:这不是山.是维苏威火山,
Ben: It's not a mountain.
历史上的大悲剧之一.
It's Vesuvius, one of the biggest disasters in history.
麦琪∶等我们开完聚会后,再来讨论这些.
Maggie: We'll see about that, after this party.
本∶妈妈不要坐在那些椅子里,上面有火山岩.
Ben: Mom, don't sit in that chair, it's got lava all over it.
麦琪∶本,我们这里现在处于紧要关头,
Maggie: Ben, we're in a crisis mode here,
在接下来的20分钟,帮我一个忙,
do me a favour and for the next twenty minutes and go out of the house
把克莉丝带出房间,你们就呆在外面.
and keep Chrissy with you.
本∶但是她一直啃我的斗牛士.
Ben: But she keeps nibbling on my gladiators.
麦琪∶去!!
Maggie: Go!!
本∶克莉丝来,快来.
Ben: Come on Chrissy, come on.
麦琪∶是,我们是西维尔家,
Maggie: Yes, we're the Seavers and we ordered the appetizers for today,
我们预定了今天的开胃食品,瑙玛来过了,
and we sent Norma away because we told her,
但是因为我们,不,
I mean my husband told her that it was the wrong day,
是我的丈夫告诉她应该是明天,所以我们就让她走了,
but it was really the right day and if I don't get those hors d'oeuvres
但是事实上真的是今天,如果我在20分钟内不能拿到拼盘,
back in the next twenty minutes I'm gonna kill him.
我就要去杀了我的丈夫.你们说什么语言的?
OK, what language do you sei habla?Carol!
开萝尔,拼盘用西班牙语怎么说?
How do you say hors d'oeuvres in Spanish?
开萝尔∶信不信由你,我是真的知道呢.
Carol: Believe it or not, I actually know that.
这个词很滑稽的,因为它相当地晦涩...
It's funny that because it's rather obscure...
麦琪∶究竟是什么!!???
Maggie: What the hell is it!!???
开萝尔∶Vo Tana.
Carol: Vo Tana.
Maggie: Vo Tana.Pronto.Today, not tomorrow, fifteen Robin Hood Lane, please tell me you
understand.Please !Hello.Hello.Hello
杰森∶宝贝儿,我不能一个人做这么多事情.
Jason: Honey, I can't do this all by myself.
麦琪∶我刚才和人讲西班牙语了.
Maggie: I just had a conversation in Spanish.
杰森∶你不会说西班牙语的.
Jason: You don't speak Spanish.
麦琪∶一点点,
Maggie: Oh, a little,
还没有足够到能向备办宴席的人传达说今天我丈夫让她离开的时候,
but not enough to convey to the caterer's that my husband was a block-
他简直就是一个死脑筋.
head when he sent the food away.
杰森∶亲爱的,整件事情都是我不好.
Jason: Oh, honey, I'm sorry about that whole date thing.
麦琪∶哦,大人物了.
Maggie: Oh, big man.
杰森∶亲爱的,我们有足够的食物.
Jason: Oh, come on honey, we got plenty of food.
麦琪∶我们没有,我还没有时间去买呢.
Maggie: No we don't, I didn_t' get the chance to go shopping yet.
杰森∶嘿,那些要倒掉的可用微波炉加热的肉丸,
Jason: Hey, how about these dumb microwaveable meatballs,
连本也不愿意吃的.
the one's even Ben won't eat.
Come on, and we got veggies Sweetheart, you can make one of those stupid dips
麦琪∶愚蠢的dips!
Maggie: Stupid dips!
杰森∶可口的.
Jason: Tasty.
麦琪∶杰森,60个有钱人和唐纳德·特朗普正在来我们肮脏的房子的路上,
Maggie: Jason, we have sixty rich people and Donald Trump on their way
现在,我们还要让他们挨饿?
to a filthy house and now we're gonna starve them?
杰森∶挨饿!亲爱的,怎么会呢?我们不是有可口的肉来招待他们吗?好吃的,甚至都舍不得浪费!
Jason: Starve!Honey, with happy tasty meat treats!Delicious, can't even spoil!
麦琪∶我不会用这些来招待他们的.
Maggie: I won't serve them.
杰森∶让我来吧.
Jason: Well, I will.
还有一半没吃完的早餐香肠,我们可以把它切掉,
And a semi eaten breakfast sausage, we'll file it down,
没有人会看出有什么不同.
nobody'll know the difference.
麦琪∶恩,伟大的杰森,我们用这些来招待他们,直到他们签好了支票再去叫救护车..
Maggie: Oh great Jason, we'll just serve them these and refuse to call the ambulance until they've signed the cheques.
杰森∶我们还有十七分钟,你想做什么?
Jason: We've got seventeen minutes, what do you want to do?
麦琪∶离开这个国家!
Maggie: Leave the country!
杰森∶麦琪,好了.我们再想想看.
Jason: Maggie, come on, put a little perspective on this.
没错,我们还只剩16分钟,
Yes, OK, we've got sixteen minutes and yes yes we have no food and yes
但是我们还没有食物,并且房子还在摇晃不稳,可是,
the house is in a shambles, but honey, we can make this work!
亲爱的,我们可以想想办法!
Yes, come on, if this happened on Perfect Strangers, would Bulky lose it?
如果这发生在完美的陌生人身上,Bulky会失去它吗?不要这么荒谬了.
Don't be ridiculous.
麦琪∶我恨这场演示!
Maggie: I hate that show!
杰森∶你喜欢露西的.露西,
Jason: You love Lucy.
记得当露西和埃塞尔在糖果厂工作时,
Lucy, remember Lucy and Ethel and they were in the candy factory and they
他们有那样很小的传送带,
had that little conveyor belt and the thing was going along like this,
所有的东西都向这样顺着传送带出来.他们...
and they were...
麦琪∶好了,好了.
Maggie: Alright!!Alright, I will cook your lousy meatballs,
我煮令你讨厌的肉丸,但是不会碰你的香肠.
but I wont' touch your sausage.
杰森∶嘿,迈克,让我来帮你吧.
Jason: Hey, Mike, let me help you with that.
迈克∶我可以!
Mike: I got it!!
麦琪∶杰森,我的灯!
Maggie: Jason, my lamp!
杰森∶还好好的呢,我没事.
Jason: No, it's alright, I'm fine.
迈克∶爸爸.你还好吧?
Mike: Dad, are you OK?
杰森∶你妈妈付钱给你了吗?
Jason: Did your mother pay you to do that?
迈克∶没有,你觉得她应该给吗?
Mike: No.Do you think she would?
开萝尔∶本,你应该看着克莉丝.
Carol: Ben, you are supposed to be watching Chrissy.
本∶而你应该是个女的.
Ben: And you're supposed to be feminine.
开萝尔∶哦,本,你太粗野了.我正在打扫你的浴室呢,本.
Carol: Oh, Carol, that' gross.I was cleaning your bathroom, Ben.
本∶好,好.
Ben: Oh, OK.
本∶克莉丝,你想看罗马人是怎么咬它的吗?
Ben: OK Chrissy, You wanna see some Romans bite it?
如果你不听话的话,我就用这种方法来对付你.
And this is what's gonna happen to you if you give me any trouble.
只是看着,可不要在家里做这个哦.哦,
Well, just keep watching and don't try this at home.
我知道我要做什么了,我要把按钮向下按的时间长一点.
Oh, I know what I have to do, I have to hold the button down longer.
哦,我今天一点也不走运.
Oh, I got no luck at all today.
麦琪∶本,你在外面带着你的山做什么?
Maggie: Ben, what are you doing out here with that mountain?
本∶是你让我拿出来的.
Ben: Well you told me to bring it out here.
麦琪∶但是你不能在车道上呀,当唐纳德·特朗普从他的直升飞机上下来的时候,
Maggie: Well, you can't be in the driveway with it,
他会怎么想?
when Donald Trump climbs out of his helicopter, what's he gonna think?
本∶谁是唐纳德·特朗普?
Ben: Who's Donald Trump?
麦琪∶他马上就要来参加聚会了.
Maggie: The man who got the date right for this party.
本∶妈妈,你在干什么?
Ben: Mom, what are you doing?
麦琪:把开胃食品托盘洗好.
Maggie: Filling out the appetizer tray.
本∶哈?
Ben: Huh?
麦琪∶在这里好像有一些过期的面包.
Maggie: There's some day old bread in here somewhere.
我要用它来做愚蠢的dip的油煎碎面包片.
I wanna make croutons for my stupid dip.
本∶克莉丝,我感觉到家里肯定是发生了什么大事情,
Ben: You know, Chrissy,
除了我的火山外.
I have feeling that there's something going on around here besides
my volcano.Yeah
杰森∶迈克,我们这里看上去还不错了.
Jason: OK, alright, we're looking pretty darn good, Mike.
迈克∶爸爸,我要说的是,
Mike: Dad, I'm telling you,
你这样把所有的椅子都摆在这里,
you're messing up bad by setting up all these chairs.
让人觉得很混乱.
Now if these people are dumb enough to pay five hundred Dollars just to
如果这些人蠢到愿意花500块来进我们家的门,你猜他们会花多少来买个椅子坐下呢
get inside the door, think what they'd pay to sit down!
杰森∶迈克,好了.哦,不到13分钟了.
Jason: Mike, come on, that's...interesting.Ooh, less than thirteen minutes.
迈克∶快想想,我们还有什么要做的?我们还有什么要做的?
Mike: Come on, what do we do?What do we do?
杰森∶我们要帮你爸爸把所有的食物都摆出来...哇,
Jason: We gonna help your mother lay out all the foo....
迈克,这些东西肯定会不错,我们不要弄坏了.
Wow, look at this it's gonna be great Mike, we're gonna pull this thing off.
麦琪∶我刚才一直在从垃圾罐头里找食物,
Maggie: I have just been routing through garbage cans for food.
这就是我和你结婚的后果.
This is what my marriage to you has led to.
杰森∶哦!亲爱的,别这样.
Jason: Oh, honey, come on.
麦琪∶我做不到!就算你叫我保守,
Maggie: Oh, I can't do it!
我还是不能用垃圾来招待客人.
Call me old-fashioned, but I just can't serve garbage.
杰森∶我们不再需要垃圾了,亲爱的,
Jason: We don't need any more trash honey, these appetizers are spectacular!
这些开胃食品很壮观的!我们还有12分钟的时间了!
And we got twelve minutes to spare!
麦琪:哦,我还没有冲凉呢.
Maggie:Oh, I haven't even showered.
杰森∶去,去,去,快去冲凉!
Jason: Go, go, go, shower!
麦琪∶本,如果你不把你的火山搬远点的话,我就要爆发了.
Maggie: Ben, if you don't take that volcano out of here, I am gonna erupt.
本∶哈.但你跟我说...
Ben: But you said to...
麦琪∶本...
Maggie: Ben...
本∶爸爸.
Ben: Dad.
杰森∶听你妈妈的.
Jason: You heard your mother.
开萝尔∶浴室都干净了,我可以在马桶上看见我的脸了.
Carol: Bathrooms are clean, I can see my face in the toilets.
迈克:好,全体通过.
Mike: Well then, that makes it unanimous.
杰森∶这该死的到底是什么,你有一个....(火山爆发,所有人都开始尖叫)
Jason: What the heck is that, you've got a...(volcano erupts, everybody screams)
本∶爆发了!爆发了!爆发了!
Ben: It works!It works!It works!
本∶你看见进油管爆炸了吗?你说我会搞砸的,哼?
Ben: Did you see that sucker blow?You tell me I'm gonna screw up now, huh?
杰森∶本,你把这里的一切全毁了.
Jason: Ben, come on, you ruined every thing here.
本∶没有,我敢肯定,既然我能成功的让它爆发一次,它就肯定能...
Ben: No, I'm sure, if I can get it to work once, it will work...
迈克∶不!不!
Mike: No!No!Not the stupid volcano, lard-brain,
不是该死的火山,傻瓜,我们说的是食物!!!
we're talking about the food!!!
开萝尔∶厨房!!
Carol: And the kitchen!!
麦琪∶还有我的头发!
Maggie: And my hair!
本∶克莉丝,好,真好!
Ben: Nice Chrissy, real nice.
克莉丝∶祝你好运.
Chrissy: Lucky.
杰森∶你的头发,你的房子,你的耻辱,对不起布丁头小姐!
Jason: Your hair, your house, your humiliation, well pardon me miss pudding head!
开萝尔∶别吵了,别吵了!客人在9分钟内就要到了.
Carol: Stop, just stop it!People will arriving here in nine minutes.
你用带有布丁的头发来用垃圾招待客人,这不是一个家了,像是一个奇异的演出.
You'll be serving
garbage with pudding in your hair...this isn't a family, it's a freak show
迈克∶好了,好了.大家都冷静下来,放松一下,不要再互相指责了...尤其是你,马桶脸.
Mike: Alright, alright, everybody just calm down and relax and stop the name-calling...especially you, toilet-face!
杰森∶这是我在最后地15分钟内听到的第一个建设性意见.
Jason: That's the first constructive suggestion I've heard in the last fifteen minutes.
开萝尔∶爸爸!!!
Carol: Dad!!!
杰森∶开萝尔,停止辩解,你弟弟一直都是听你的.
Jason: Oh stop whining, Carol, your brother's been right about you for years.
迈克∶对了,我可以用我的湿-干真空吸尘器,会马上就把这里打扫的干干净净.
Mike: Alright, alright, alright!I'm gonna use my wet-dry vac and I'll have this place clean in a snap.
麦琪∶你在哪里弄来的湿-干真空吸尘器?
Maggie: Where'd you get a wet-dry vac?
迈克∶我有就是了.
Mike: Let's just say I got one, alright?
杰森:他现在是唯一一个想着筹资工作的孩子.
Jason: Our son is the only person around here in this family,
who still cares about this fundraiser work!
本:等一下,爸爸的筹资应该是明天.
Ben: Wait a minute, I thought Dad's fundraiser was tomorrow.
迈克∶嘿,如果坏掉了也没有关系,我还有一个.
Mike: Hey look, if it's broken, it's OK, I got another one.
比萨饼男孩∶这是你的比萨饼.
Pizza boy: Here's your pizza.
迈克∶什么?
Mike: What?
比萨饼男孩∶你的比萨饼;你定的.
Pizza boy: Your pizza, the one you ordered.
杰森∶化险为夷了!有人定了比萨饼!
Jason: That saves the day!Somebody ordered a pizza!
迈克∶哦!是的!
Mike: Oh, yeah!
比萨饼男孩∶一共是9块8毛5.
Pizza boy: That'll be nine eighty five.
杰森∶嘿,给你10块,我的心情太好了,不用找了.
Jason: Hey, hey, hey, that's alright.There's ten Bucks, I'm in such a good mood, keep the change.
比萨饼男孩∶哇,Cussman先生,我真是感激涕零.
Pizza boy: Wow, I may weep Mr.Cussman.
杰森∶Cussman... Cussman,哦,你要...
Jason: Cussman...Cussman, oh, you want...
迈克∶原谅我们.爸爸,
Mike: Ah, excuse us, excuse us.
现在刚好有食物送到我们面前,
Dad, we have food right here staring us in the face,
而客人在8分钟内就要到了,你要怎么做?
and the people are showing up here in eight minutes, what are you doing?
杰森∶迈克,我不能跟他说谎.
Jason: Mike, I can't lie to the guy.
迈克∶爸爸,
Mike: But Dad, think of all the people you're gonna be helping with your
想想你的医疗所将要帮助的那些人...
health clinic.
杰森∶迈克,现在不得不撒谎了.小伙子,
Jason: Mike, there's never a time to lie.Son, we ordered five pizzas, not one.
我们31分钟前订了5个比萨饼,而不是1个,所以它们都应该免费.
And that was thirty one minutes ago, so they're free.
比萨饼男孩∶哦,拜托.
Pizza boy: Oh, come on.
杰森∶不要和我瞎搅和了,孩子,我没有什么好失去的了.
Jason: Don't mess with me kid, I got nothing to lose.
迈克∶我以为你不会说谎的.
Mike: And I thought there was never a time to lie.
杰森∶我说谎了!我说谎了!我不是Cussman,
Jason: I was lying!I was lying!
我是一个心理学家,但是,我是真的需要这些食物.
look, I'm not Cussman, I'm a psychiatrist, but I need this food
迈克∶是台很神奇的机器吧?
Mike: Is this a fabulous machine, or what?
杰森∶好了,一切都准备好了,我们还有5分钟的时间去洗澡和穿衣服.
Jason: Alright, everything's all cleaned up, we got five minutes to shower shampoo and get dressed.
麦琪∶一个就可以吃完的比萨饼.
Maggie: Alright, bite-sized pizza.
杰森∶亲爱的,我不该叫你布丁头.
Jason: Oh honey, I'm sorry I called you pudding head.
麦琪∶恩,我也不该说我宁愿你把我们的婚期搞错.
Maggie: Mmm, and I'm sorry I said I wished you'd got our wedding date wrong.
杰森∶你什么时候说过这个?
Jason: When'd you say that?
麦琪∶今天说了若干次.
Maggie: Several times today.
杰森∶如果我们一起洗会快很多.
Jason: Be faster if we shower together.
开萝尔∶啊,水槽塞住了.
Carol: Oh great, this sink is clogged.
迈克∶嘿,对湿-干真空吸尘器的拥有者---本人来说,
Mike: Hey, that's no problem at all for the owner of a wet-dry vac.
这是小事一庄,你们俩走开,
Just step aside, both of you.Allow me.
只要把水龙头放在水槽口,就可以用吸尘器把堵塞物吹走.
Just put your hose in the right port, and blow your problems away.
你们看,我根本是不费吹灰之力.
If you'll notice, I'm not even working up a sweat.
麦琪∶开萝尔!
Maggie: Carol!
杰森:怎么回事?
Jason: What's going on?
麦琪∶食物!
Maggie: The food!
迈克∶妈妈,爸爸,
Mike: Mom, Dad, take it easy on the little guy,
不要怪这个小家伙了,他只是听了开萝尔的指示.
he was only doing what Carol told him to do.
麦琪∶哦,谢谢!好消息,杰森,我打电话给Cussman家,想问问他们有没有食物,结果他们说他们已经定了比萨饼,马上就可以送过来了.
Maggie: Oh, thank you.Oh, great news Jason, I called the Cussman's to see if they had any food at all, and they are expecting a pizza!And just as soon as it gets there, they're gonna send it right over.
杰森∶恩,Cussman家不会有比萨饼了.
Jason: Yeah, well the Cussman' s aren't getting a pizza.
麦琪∶什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森∶已经被我半路拦截了.
Jason: I already hijacked their pie.
麦琪∶真是太疯狂了.
Maggie: This is truly pathetic.
杰森∶我们还有4分钟的洗澡时间.
Jason: Alright, let's go, four minutes to shower honey.
麦琪∶拿这样的食物来招待客人的人是不用洗澡的.
Maggie: Ah, what's the point, people who serve food like this are beyond showers.
杰森:我会跟他们说是我的错.
Jason: I'll tell everybody it was all my fault.
麦琪:亲爱的,也许装的伤心一些有利于筹资.
Maggie: Oh honey, maybe looking very very sad will help you raise money.
杰森∶恩,只是希望媒体不要来.
Jason: Yeah, well let's just hope they don't run the pictures.
麦琪∶什么?
Maggie: The what?
杰森∶媒体,纽约时报,
Jason: The pictures honey, the New York Times, they're coming today,
他们说今天要来的,我没有告诉你吗?
didn't I tell you?
麦琪∶没有,你没有跟我说过.那才是今天的演出.
Maggie: No, you didn't.Oh, that' probably the Today Show.
杰森∶哦,有人提前来了.
Jason: Oh, people coming early.
麦琪∶唐纳德·特朗普,欢迎光临.
Maggie: Donald Trump, welcome to my home.
臭虫∶我以最快的速度赶过来的.
Stinky: I came as fast as I could.
杰森∶哦,不是现在臭虫.
Jason: Oh, not now Stinky.
臭虫∶但是我有食物.
Stinky: But I have food.
麦琪∶什么?哦!
Maggie: What?Oh, Oreos!
麦琪∶甜点!
Jason: Roundshwegger!
麦琪∶哦!奶酪!
Maggie: Oh heck, cheese!
杰森∶一袋马铃薯!
Jason: Sack of potatoes!
麦琪∶花生!
Maggie: Obies!
麦琪∶花生酱!
Jason: Peanut Butter!
麦琪∶玉米片!
Maggie: Corn chips!
杰森∶泡火腿!
Jason: Pickled ham!
麦琪∶?????
Maggie: ?????
杰森∶牛肉干,呵呵.
Jason: Beef jerky.Yeah.
臭虫∶我希望够了,这是我房间里所有的食物.
Stinky: I hope it's enough, that's all I had in my room.
麦琪∶哦!臭虫,你太棒了.
Maggie: Oh, Stinky, you are wonderful.
杰森∶你怎么知道我们需要食物?
Jason: How'd you know we needed food?
臭虫∶本打电话给我的.
Stinky: Ben called me.
麦琪∶我们的本.
Maggie: Our Ben.
臭虫:我把手风琴拿来了,希望给大家带来快乐.
Stinky: And I brought my accordian in case you wanna get down and get funky.
杰森∶大家都随意一点,随意.
Jason: now just get everybody casual now.Casual.
麦琪∶随意.
Maggie: Casual.
杰森∶有人要去开门.好了,我去.
Jason: Somebody should get the door.No, I'll get it.
臭虫∶如果我能帮上什么忙,尽管说.
Stinky: If I can do anything to help, just ask.
杰森∶你好,请进,欢迎光临.
Jason: Yeah.Hello, come in, welcome.
理查∶你好,我是理查.
Rich: Hi, I'm Rich.
迈克∶天了,这些人都很直截了当.
Mike: Boy, these people just come right out and say it.
杰森∶小心开车,谢谢你.多谢你的捐款,理查.
Jason: Drive safely, thank you.Listen, thank you so much for that contribution, Rich.
理查:我今天下午过的很美妙.
Rich: I had a fabulous afternoon.
理查的妻子∶你们今天提供的食物是你们的确需要捐赠的最好的证明.
Rich's wife: Your eclectic display of food was an eloquent statement on
the needy causes of today.
麦琪∶我们认为,没必要假装.
Maggie: Well, we figured...why put on a show.
杰森∶我没有想到你会捐这么多.
Jason: And hey listen, your donation was really more than I ever could have hoped for.
理查∶我是认为,如果有更多的人对他们自己很满意,
Rich: Well I figured, the more people we have feeling good about themselves,
那么就会有更少的人会认为我们是不仁的贫民老板.
the less people we have calling me a heartless slum lord.
杰森∶一定会记得这句话的.
Jason: Words to live by.
理查∶再见.
Rich: Ta-ta.
麦琪∶再见.
Maggie: Ta-ta.
杰森∶谢谢你.
Jason: Thank you.
理查的妻子∶再见亲爱的,很高兴见到你.
Rich's wife: Good bye dear, nice to meet you.
麦琪∶我也是.
Maggie: Nice meeting you.
杰森和麦琪∶喔!
Jason and Maggie: Woo!
杰森∶我们成功了.
Jason: We did it.
开萝尔∶你怎么能说成功了呢?我都没有见到唐纳德·特朗普.
Carol: How can you say that?I didn't even get to meet Donald Trump.
臭虫∶哦!我刚才忘记说他来过了.
Stinky: Oh, I forgot that dude was here.
麦琪∶什么?
Maggie: What?
臭虫∶你们在洗澡的时候,他来吃了点牛肉干和一些果汁,然后就走了.
Stinky: When you were showering he had some beef jerky, a little Cool-ade and then left.
开萝尔∶你见到唐纳德·特朗普了!
Carol: You met Donald Trump!
臭虫∶是呀,他是谁?
Stinky: Yeah, who is he?
迈克∶我不是唯一一个愚蠢的人.
Mike: I'm not the only stupid one around here.
臭虫∶但是他让我把这个给你.
Stinky: But he told me to give you this.
杰森∶一万美元!!!
Jason: Ten thousand Dollars!!!
本∶来买一点牛肉干和果汁!
Ben: For some beef jerky and Cool-ade!
杰森∶嘿,嘿,我们今天真是做的太好了!
Jason: Hey, hey, we did alright guys!
麦琪∶哦!我们成功了!
Maggie: Oh, we did!
杰森∶没错.在压力下才能显示出人的本性,
Jason: Yes.You know the true test of character is grace under pressure,
我认为我们今天都表现的非常好.我们像一家人一样,
and I think we all scored pretty darn well today.
像团队一样.没有人小气,
Come on, we pulled together as a family, as a team.
没有人自私,没有人不讲理.
Nobody got petty, nobody got selfish, nobody got irrational.
麦琪∶对对!
Maggie: Here here!
杰森∶让我们在以后的多事之秋时都谨记今天.
Jason: Now, let's remember that in the troubled times ahead.
本∶你们能这样说,我觉得真的很开心,
Ben: I'm really glad you made that speech, because for a while there,
因为我一度在想,我们做的事情一点意义也没有.杰森∶呵呵,
I was starting to think there was no point in what we were doing.
本,不是你一个人这样想.我也一度对我们的愚蠢的行为产生过怀疑.
Jason: Ah, you're not alone Ben.
00:21:36,600
For a while I had my doubts about this whole silly episode.